<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
        cq:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:16:35.437+02:00"
        cq:lastModifiedBy="admin"
        cq:template="/conf/demo-site/settings/wcm/templates/page-content"
        jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
        jcr:title="Surfing"
        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/page">
        <root
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/container">
            <container
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/container">
                <title
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/title"/>
                <container
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/container"
                    layout="responsiveGrid">
                    <text
                        jcr:created="{Date}2020-06-13T17:14:32.497+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:14:40.785+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/text"
                        text="&lt;p>Surfing is a surface water pastime in which the wave rider, referred to as a surfer, rides on the forward part, or face, of a moving wave, which usually carries the surfer towards the shore. Waves suitable for surfing are primarily found in the ocean, but can also be found in lakes or rivers in the form of a standing wave or tidal bore. However, surfers can also utilize artificial waves such as those from boat wakes and the waves created in artificial wave pools.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Mick Corbett at Cow Bombie in Western Australia&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The term surfing usually refers to the act of riding a wave using a board, regardless of the stance. There are several types of boards. The native peoples of the Pacific, for instance, surfed waves on alaia, paipo, and other such craft, and did so on their belly and knees. The modern-day definition of surfing, however, most often refers to a surfer riding a wave standing on a surfboard; this is also referred to as stand-up surfing.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;"
                        textIsRich="true"/>
                    <image
                        jcr:created="{Date}2020-06-13T17:14:46.851+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:14:49.563+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/image"
                        fileReference="/content/dam/demo-site/surfing.jpg"/>
                    <title
                        jcr:created="{Date}2020-06-13T17:14:54.839+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:15:35.454+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        jcr:title="Learning"
                        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/title"
                        type="h2"/>
                    <text_943987421
                        jcr:created="{Date}2020-06-13T17:14:57.890+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:15:42.880+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/text"
                        text="&lt;p>Many popular surfing destinations have surf schools and surf camps that offer lessons. Surf camps for beginners and intermediates are multi-day lessons that focus on surfing fundamentals. They are designed to take new surfers and help them become proficient riders. All-inclusive surf camps offer overnight accommodations, meals, lessons and surfboards. Most surf lessons begin with instruction and a safety briefing on land, followed by instructors helping students into waves on longboards or &amp;quot;softboards&amp;quot;. The softboard is considered the ideal surfboard for learning, due to the fact it is safer, and has more paddling speed and stability than shorter boards. Funboards are also a popular shape for beginners as they combine the volume and stability of the longboard with the manageable size of a smaller surfboard.[20] New and inexperienced surfers typically learn to catch waves on softboards around the 210 to 240 cm (7 to 8 ft) funboard size. Due to the softness of the surfboard the chance of getting injured is substantially minimized.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Typical surfing instruction is best performed one-on-one, but can also be done in a group setting. The most popular surf locations offer perfect surfing conditions for beginners, as well as challenging breaks for advanced students. The ideal conditions for learning would be small waves that crumble and break softly, as opposed to the steep, fast-peeling waves desired by more experienced surfers. When available, a sandy seabed is generally safer.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Surfing can be broken into several skills: Paddling strength, Positioning to catch the wave, timing, and balance. Paddling out requires strength, but also the mastery of techniques to break through oncoming waves (duck diving, eskimo roll). Take-off positioning requires experience at predicting the wave set and where they will break. The surfer must pop up quickly as soon as the wave starts pushing the board forward. Preferred positioning on the wave is determined by experience at reading wave features including where the wave is breaking.[21] Balance plays a crucial role in standing on a surfboard. Thus, balance training exercises are a good preparation. Practicing with a Balance board or swing boarding helps novices master the art.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The repetitive cycle of paddling, popping up, and balancing requires stamina, explosivity, and near-constant core stabilization. Having a proper warm up routine can help prevent injuries.[22]&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;"
                        textIsRich="true"/>
                    <title_899009088
                        jcr:created="{Date}2020-06-13T17:15:01.517+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:15:59.702+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        jcr:title="Maneuvers"
                        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/title"
                        type="h2"/>
                    <text_2092697134
                        jcr:created="{Date}2020-06-13T17:15:05.134+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2020-06-13T17:16:35.435+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="demo-site/components/text"
                        text="&lt;p>Standup surfing begins when the surfer paddles toward shore in an attempt to match the speed of the wave (the same applies whether the surfer is standup paddling, bodysurfing, boogie-boarding or using some other type of watercraft, such as a waveski or kayak). Once the wave begins to carry the surfer forward, the surfer stands up and proceeds to ride the wave. The basic idea is to position the surfboard so it is just ahead of the breaking part (whitewash) of the wave. A common problem for beginners is being able to catch the wave at all.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Surfers' skills are tested by their ability to control their board in difficult conditions, riding challenging waves, and executing maneuvers such as strong turns and cutbacks (turning board back to the breaking wave) and carving (a series of strong back-to-back maneuvers). More advanced skills include the floater (riding on top of the breaking curl of the wave), and off the lip (banking off the breaking wave). A newer addition to surfing is the progression of the air whereby a surfer propels off the wave entirely up into the air, and then successfully lands the board back on the wave.&lt;br>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The tube ride is considered to be the ultimate maneuver in surfing. As a wave breaks, if the conditions are ideal, the wave will break in an orderly line from the middle to the shoulder, enabling the experienced surfer to position themselves inside the wave as it is breaking. This is known as a tube ride. Viewed from the shore, the tube rider may disappear from view as the wave breaks over the rider's head. The longer the surfer remains in the tube, the more successful the ride. This is referred to as getting tubed, barrelled, shacked or pitted. Some of the world's best known waves for tube riding include Pipeline on the North shore of Oahu, Teahupoo in Tahiti and G-Land in Java. Other names for the tube include &amp;quot;the barrel&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;the pit&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Hanging ten and hanging five are moves usually specific to long boarding. Hanging Ten refers to having both feet on the front end of the board with all of the surfer's toes off the edge, also known as nose-riding. Hanging Five is having just one foot near the front, with five toes off the edge.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Cutback: Generating speed down the line and then turning back to reverse direction.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Floater: Suspending the board atop the wave. Very popular on small waves.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Top-Turn: Turn off the top of the wave. Sometimes used to generate speed and sometimes to shoot spray.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Airs/Aerials: These maneuvers have been becoming more and more prevalent in the sport in both competition and free surfing. An air is when the surfer can achieve enough speed and approach a certain type of section of a wave that is supposed to act as a ramp and launch the surfer above the lip line of the wave, “catching air”, and landing either in the transition of the wave or the whitewash when hitting a close-out section.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Airs can either be straight airs or rotational airs. Straight airs have minimal rotation if any, but definitely no more rotation than 90 degrees. Rotational airs require a rotation of 90 degrees or more depending on the level of the surfer.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;"
                        textIsRich="true"/>
                </container>
            </container>
        </root>
    </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
